漫威影业出品
■
翻译
夜魔草
时间轴
夜魔倩
夜魔念
时间轴
校对
夜魔K  夜魔奶
后期
8T  鱼骨头
总监
夜魔奶
更多双语字幕
敬请登陆关注
新浪微博@ZiMuZu
www.abcsub.com
新浪微博
@小逗比_美剧派
倾情奉献
新浪微博
@小逗比_美剧派
倾情奉献
夜
魔
侠
第一季  第九集
我都有点担心你是不是不会再出现了
Started to wonder if you'd ever turn up again.
我最近
Yeah, I've, uh...
挺忙的
been busy.
如果你想告解  我就在里面
Well, I'll be inside, you wanna take confession.
神父
Uh, Father?
现在可以问你要那杯拿铁吗
I was wondering if I could take you up on that latte?
加糖吗
Sugar?
不用
No.
说说
So...
你有什么心事  马修
what's on your mind, Matthew?
一眼就看出来了
Wasn't that hard to find out.
这一带的人还记得烈焰拳手杰克·默多克呢
People still remember "Battlin' Jack Murdock" around these parts...
也记得他儿子的事
and what happened to his son.
就算喝着拿铁  告解内容也不外传
Seal of confession still applies, even over lattes.
如果你担心的是这个的话
That what you're worried about.
你相信有魔鬼吗  神父
Do you believe in the Devil, Father?
这个理念吗
You mean... as a concept?
不
No.
你认为魔鬼存在吗
Do you believe he exists?
在这世间  我们之中
In this world, among us.
你想听简短的回答  还是长的
You want the short answer or the long one?
事实
Just the truth.
我上神学院时
When I was in seminary...
我更多是好学  而非虔诚
I was more studious than pious, more...
比我大部分的同辈有更多怀疑
skeptical than most of my peers.
我有个想法
I had this notion...
我很乐意跟任何
which I was more than willing to speak about, at length,
我能堵到的人畅谈
to whoever I could corner...
我认为魔鬼
that the Devil...
根本不重要
was inconsequential.
不过是大局中的小人物
Minor figure in the grand scheme.
你可不怎么像个天主教徒
Not very Catholic of you.
是啊
Uh-huh, yeah.
不过我要说  在《圣经》中
In my defense, in the scriptures,
希伯来语"撒旦"一词
the Hebrew word "Satan"
其实是"敌人"的意思
actually means "Adversary."
可适用于任何一个敌手
It's applied to any antagonist.
天使  人类  毒蛇  国王
Angels and humans, serpents and kings.
中世纪的神学家重新诠释了这些经文
Medieval theologians reinterpreted those passages
将其具化成一个单一的可怕敌人
to be about a single monstrous enemy.
我当时年轻气盛  确信自己想通了原因
And, in my youthful zeal, I was certain I knew why...
为了政治目的
propaganda.
夸大其词  好让人们来教堂
Played up to drive people into the church.
那么你不相信他的存在
So you don't believe he exists.
我说完了吗
Am I done talking?
抱歉
Sorry.
多年后  我去了卢旺达
Years later, I was in Rwanda...
想协助当地教堂
trying to help local churches
为难民提供帮助和庇护
provide aid and sanctuary to refugees.
我跟村里的长者走得很近
I'd become close with the village elder,
嘉希吉
Gahiji.
他和他家人受到大家尊敬
He and his family had the respect of everybody,
胡图族和图西族都尊敬他们
Hutu and Tutsi alike.
他帮助所有人  撑过饥饿  瘟疫
He'd helped them all... through famines, disease.
民兵组织喜欢逼迫
The militia liked to force
胡图族村民杀害他们的邻居
Hutu villagers to murder their neighbors...
用砍刀杀人
with machetes.
但没人愿意对嘉希吉动手
But nobody would raise a hand against Gahiji.
他们说  "我们怎么能杀这样的圣人"
They said, "Well... how can we kill such a holy man?"
于是民兵头领派去了士兵
So the militia commander sent soldiers...
下令要当着全村的面
with orders to cut his head off...
砍下他的头
in front of the entire village.
嘉希吉甚至没有反抗
Gahiji didn't try to put up a fight.
只求跟家人道别
Just asked for the chance to say goodbye to his family.
等他道别完了  就连士兵都不愿杀他了
By the time he was done, even the soldiers didn't wanna kill him.
于是他们去找指挥官
So they went to their commander
请求开枪射杀他
and asked permission to shoot him.
至少让他死得痛快
At least give him a quick death.
指挥官想见见这个人
The commander wanted to meet this man...
毕竟他赢得了那么多人的尊敬
who had won the respect of so many.
他去找了嘉希吉
He went to Gahiji...
在他的小屋里  跟他谈了数小时
talked with him in his hut... for many hours.
然后他把他拽了出来  当着全村的面
Then he dragged him out in front of his village
把他砍成了碎块
and hacked him to pieces...
还砍死了他全家人
along with his entire family.
在那个杀死了嘉希吉的人身上
In that man who took Gahiji's life...
我看到了魔鬼
I saw the Devil.
所以是的  马修
So yes, Matthew...
我相信魔鬼就在人间
I believe he walks among us...
他有很多形态
taking many forms.
如果你可以阻止他
What if you could have stopped him...
让他再不能伤害别人呢
from ever hurting anyone again?
怎么阻止他
Stopped him how?
这并没有改变什么  本
This doesn't change anything, Ben.
只不过现在我们知道方片K是谁了
Except now we know who your king of diamonds is.
你看新闻了吗  一切都变了
You see the news? Everything's changed.
威尔逊·菲斯克向市民保证将带来更好的明天
菲斯克抢先一步  我们不能"曝光"他了
Fisk has gotten out in front of being dragged into the spotlight.
我主编当他是基督再临
My editor thinks he's the Second Coming.
整个城市都这么认为
Hell, the whole city does.
那我们继续挖掘啊
So, we just... We keep digging.
我一直在挖
I've been doing that.
网上从毫无菲斯克的消息
Internet went from nothing on Fisk
一夜之间变成到处是地狱厨房
to filled with three-hanky stories
一个可怜的胖小子的煽情故事
about a poor little fat kid from Hell's Kitchen.
12岁被父亲抛弃  母亲一年后也去世
Abandoned by his father when he was 12. Mother died a year later.
现在再看他  人模狗样  胸怀梦想
Now look at him. Boot straps and a big dream.
肯定有人知情
Somebody knows something.
只是要找到合适的人  用合适的语气
It's just a matter of asking the right people the right questions
问合适的问题
in the right tone of voice.
嗯  这只会害了你自己
Yeah, that's how you get yourself hurt.
我也总这么跟他们说
That's what I keep telling them.
或许他们会听你的
Maybe they'll listen to you.
本·尤里克  马特·默多克
Ben Urich, Matt Murdock.
"何必操心律所"律师
Attorney at Why the Hell Bother.
-默多克先生  -叫我马特
- Mr. Murdock. - Matt.
我合伙人认为我们该采取法律手段追查此事
My partner thinks we should be pursuing this through the legal system.
这样更安全
A lot safer that way.
那我们都爬到被子下面得了
Well, why don't we all just crawl under the covers, then?
-不  凯伦  -真抱歉
- No, Karen... - Well, I'm sorry,
但如果这一切都是菲斯克在搞鬼
but if Fisk is really behind everything that has happened,
那我们得采取行动
then we need to do something.
如果只有我们在找他  那我会同意
If we were the only ones after him, I'd tend to agree.
你一个朋友昨天晚上来找我了
Friend of yours came to see me the other night...
面具男
the man in the mask.
-恐怖分子警察杀手  -自称是被栽赃了
- Terrorist cop-killer. - Says he was framed.
我还能说我是美国队长呢
I could say I'm Captain America,
我头上也没长翅膀
but it doesn't put wings on my head.
他想干什么
What did he want?
跟我们一样  揭露菲斯克
Same thing we do... expose Fisk.
我从他给我的U盘里打出了这个
I printed this from a thumb drive he gave me.
天呐
Oh, my God!
他说菲斯克是爆炸  枪击警察的幕后主使
Told me Fisk was behind the bombings and shooting those cops...
还说他把半数警力捏在手里
said he owns half the police...
他们还帮忙除掉俄国人来着
that they helped him take down the Russians.
我不懂  你既然掌握了这些
But I don't understand. If you have all of this, then...
只是传闻  无从证实就不能出版
Hearsay. Can't print any of it without corroboration, can you?
他可能只是丢烟雾弹
He could just be throwing smoke.
他才杀了布雷克警探啊
I mean, he just killed Detective Blake.
他说是布雷克的搭档霍夫曼干的
Said Blake's partner Hoffman did it,
可能是受菲斯克之命
probably on Fisk's orders.
但没错  这我想到了
But yeah, it occurred to me.
你可以去找霍夫曼
You could talk to Hoffman.
试了  他已经没影了
Tried. He's in the wind.
或者是沉入河底了  不管怎样
Or bottom of the river. Either way...
他耸肩了
He just shrugged.
抱歉
Sorry.
等等  那联合建筑的钱呢
Wait, what about the Union Allied money?
可以将这笔钱跟菲斯克联系起来吗
Is there a way that we can tie it directly to Fisk?
或许吧
Maybe.
据面具男说  一个叫
According to the Mask, a man named,
利兰·奥斯利的人负责管账
Leland Owlsley runs the books.
但自从他袭击了奥斯利
But since getting roughed up by him,
他身边就一直有菲斯克的保镖保护
Owlsley's been surrounded by Fisk's security.
无法接近他
Can't get anywhere near him.
还有詹姆斯·韦斯利也一样
Same goes with, uh, James Wesley,
就是你说雇你们为希里辩护的那个人
the guy you said hired you to defend Healy.
面具男找本帮忙
Look, the Mask came to Ben for help.
我不管菲斯克多有钱
And I don't care how rich Fisk is,
没人能彻底抹去他们的过去
nobody can totally erase their past.
这世上
I mean, somewhere out there,
肯定有相关的文件  证人
there has to be a piece of paper, a witness...
和真相
the truth.
联合全球公司呢
What about Confederated Global?
雇我们为希里辩护的西装男
The suit that hired us to defend Healy
在菲斯克发表讲话的时候  就站在他身旁
standing right next to Fisk when he gave his big speech.
我查了  根据通信委员会文件
I looked into that. According to FCC filings,
菲斯克上报的大部分收入都来自联合全球公司
Confed Global's where Fisk gets most of his reported income.
好  那我们分析一下
All right, let's play this out.
如果菲斯克跟联合全球公司有关
If Fisk is connected to Confed Global,
那他就跟维斯莫尔-霍特承包公司有关
that means he's involved in Westmeyer-Holt Contracting, which...
维斯莫尔-霍特在强迫
Westmeyer-Holt is strong-arming
其住户离开受租金管制保护的公寓楼
tenants out of their rent-controlled apartments.
他们受雇于一个叫阿曼德·徒利的人
Um, they were hired by a guy named Armand Tully.
那个恶房东
The slumlord?
兰德曼-扎克律所说他去度假了
Landman and Zack say he's on vacation
在一个没人念得出名字的小岛上
on an island that no one can pronounce,
而且岛上只有椰子做的土电话
where they use coconuts as phones.
又一个消失的线索
Another connection in the wind.
维斯莫尔-霍特联系到联合再到菲斯克
Westmeyer-Holt to Confed to Fisk.
我们拉这根线  看能拽出什么来
We pull that thread, see what it unravels.
我对这个面具男还是不放心
Still not sure about this mask guy.
他没伤害本  也没伤害我
He didn't hurt Ben and he didn't hurt me.
我随时都愿意信地狱厨房的恶魔也不信菲斯克
I'll take the Devil of Hell's Kitchen over Fisk any day.
而且  他多厉害啊
Plus, he kicks ass.
不  你们真该看看
No, you should've seen the way
他在雨里翻跟头的样子
that he was flipping around in the rain.
如果他那么厉害  又何必找到本
Well, if he's such a badass, why did he come to Ben?
何不自己扳倒菲斯克呢
Why not just take Fisk down himself?
或许他知道有些路是不能回头的
Maybe he knows there's some roads you can't come back from.
最新民调显示  你的支持率在上升
Our latest polls show your approval numbers rising...
跨党派  跨种族  不论贫富
across political, ethnic and economic lines.
新建设  西52街和第九大道  混用住宅  酒店  零售  四层复式楼
志愿者组织免税已获批准
The 501C3 has been approved,
政治行动委员会已经在积极捐款了
so the PAC is actively making donations,
切瑞参议员的办公室请求见面
and Senator Cherryh's office has asked for a meet.
早餐吧
Breakfast.
不管他们提出什么  拒绝第一个提议
Reject the first place they suggest.
霍夫曼警探呢
How about Detective Hoffman?
内务处的线人称
Our sources in IAB tell me
他本该就市综合医院的事
he was supposed to give a follow-up statement
给出补充供述
about what happened at Metro-General.
但却没出现
He never showed.
必须了结此事
We need to put this behind us.
如果他还在城里  我们就能找到他
If he's still in the city, we'll find him.
如果他跑了呢
If he isn't?
还是能找到他  只是要多花点时间
We'll still find him. It might just take a little longer.
面具男呢
And the man in the mask?
只要有机会抓住他  当局有充分理由
The authorities are motivated to shoot on sight...
将他就地击毙
if they have the opportunity.
他远不像之前那样活跃了
He's not nearly as active as he has been in the past.
或许他放弃了
Maybe he's given up.
或许他只是对目标选择更谨慎了
Maybe he's just choosing his targets more carefully.
我叫你在外面等的
Hey, I said you need to wait outside.
没事  弗兰西斯  谢谢
It's all right, Francis. Thank you.
抱歉  信君
My apologies, Nobu-san.
如果我早知道你要来
If I had known you were coming...
他不在乎住宿条件如何
He doesn't care for the accommodations.
你再敢乱翻译我的话
Misspeak my words again...
我就拔下你的舌头
and I will have your tongue.
韦斯利只是客气
Wesley is just trying to be polite.
客套该结束了
The time for pleasantries... is at an end.
你承诺给我一个城市街区
I was promised a city block
以感激我对你投资的协助
in return for my aid in your ventures.
有一栋
There is a...
出租房
a tenement in, um...
就在这地方
this particular area...
房客很不好赶走
it has proven troublesome to vacate.
但还有其他街区要空出来了  如果你...
But we have other blocks coming up if you...
这个
This one.
我不记得
I don't recall...
具体保证过给你哪个地方
guaranteeing a specific block.
你得耐心等待
You'll need to be patient...
要么就另选一个
or choose another.
我要满足特定的要求
I am bound by certain requirements.
我也要向上头交代
Even I have those I must answer to.
在码头受挫之后
After the setback at the docks...
我不能再受挫了
I can afford no further disruptions.
尽一切努力  一定要快
Do what you must, but do it quickly.
韦斯利
Wesley?
不管我们解决的方式有多小心翼翼
Regardless of how carefully it's handled,
毕竟你现在是登记的业主了
you're now the owner of record.
负面影响可能要付出昂贵的代价
The negative publicity could prove costly.
我的组织会补偿你们这部分费用
My organization will compensate you for the expense.
多谢了  但没必要
Well, the offer's appreciated, but unnecessary.
但有个问题
There is, however, a problem
你可以帮我解决  以答谢我的帮助
that you could aid me in solving, in return for my help.
这个问题对我们都是个麻烦
One that has inconvenienced us both.
黑衣男
The man in black.
他确实比预想中更难对付
He's proven to be more difficult to address than expected.
他决心坚定  而且身手不凡
Possessed of determination and unusual talents.
我们得找到势均力敌的人
We must match him in kind.
或许请你们组织调一位高手过来
A specialist, perhaps, from your organization.
我知道一个有这种身手的人
I know of one with such skills.
但会很难找到我们的敌人
But finding our enemy will be difficult.
他最近  谨慎多了
He has become... cautious.
是啊
Yes, he has.
但情感
But emotion...
可以让最慎重的人变得鲁莽
can turn the most circumspect of men careless.
不  我不是那个意思
No, that's not what I'm saying.
听上去就是啊
Well, it sure sounds like it.
如果菲斯克真是把我的城市炸上天的人
Hey, if Fisk really is the guy that blew the hell out of my city,
还射伤了警察  并追杀你
shot those cops and went after you,
那不会有人比我更想看他栽跟头了
then nobody wants to see him take it on the nuts more than me.
这我或许能把你比下去
No, I might have you edged out on that.
好吧  除了在场的人
Okay, present company excluded.
我只是想说  阿曼德·徒利查不下去了
All I'm saying is Armand Tully is a dead end.
你们查到什么了吗
You find something out?
我跟玛茜私下沟通了一下
I, um, did a little back-channeling with Marci.
好吧  恶心  你查到什么了
Okay, ew, just... What did you get?
徒利的确在小岛上
Tully really is on an island
他用联合全球公司买下他在地狱厨房
that he bought with the money that Confed Global is paying him
所有房产的钱买下了那座小岛
for all his real estate holdings in Hell's Kitchen.
那这就是联系啊
Then, that's the link!
可以将菲斯克直接
I mean, it ties Fisk directly
与租户案相联系起来
to what's happening in the tenement case.
不行
No, it doesn't.
根据记录
According to the records,
交易今早才完成
the deal just went through this morning.
那么
So...
那么此前案子中发生的事
So everything that happened with the case up till now
都发生在菲斯克是在案业主之前  责任都在徒利
was before Fisk was the owner on record. All falls on Tully.
好吧  那我们就去找徒利  让他背叛菲斯克
Okay, so we go after Tully. We get him to turn on Fisk.
嗯  他的那个小岛
Yeah, that island he's on?
没有引渡协议
No extradition agreement.
又是死路一条
It's another dead end.
早上好
Buenos días.
你好  卡德纳斯太太
Hola, señora Cardenas.
图书馆在哪里
¿Dónde está la biblioteca?
你刚刚是在问她图书馆在哪
You just asked her where the library is.
快进来
Entra, entra.
出什么事了吗
No está bien.
菲斯克先生开价双倍的协议金
El señor Fisk nos ofreció el doble de dinero.
他们把协议金翻了倍  想让租户搬走
They doubled the offer to get the tenants to move out.
我的邻居们都在考虑接受了
Mis vecinos piensan tomarlo.
-该死  -怎么了
- Oh, damn it. - What?
她的邻居在考虑接受
Her neighbors are thinking about taking it.
或许他们是该接受
Maybe they should.
不  叫她坚守立场
No! Tell her to stand firm.
我们说过会帮她  我们就会帮她的
We told her we're gonna help her and that's what we're gonna do.
他不会放弃的  他希望你也不要放弃
Él no se va a rendir y no quiere que tu lo hagas tampoco.
真是个好孩子
Such a good boy.
我想我能说服他们
Creo que los puedo hacer cambiar de opinión.
至少说服足够多的人  以改变局势
Suficientos como para ser una diferencia.
她觉得她能说服他们
She thinks she can change their minds.
至少说服足够多的人  足以改变局势
Enough of them maybe to make a difference.
我不会接受  那是我的家
I no take! This my home.
我们要抗争  是不是
We fight, yes?
没错
Yes, sí.
他是个好人
He is good man.
你们
All of you...
都是好人
good.
你不该那样
You shouldn't have done that.
怎么了  不是要为小人物的权利抗争吗
What? Fight for the rights of the little guy, right?
菲斯克要那栋楼  他不得手不会罢休的
Fisk wants the tenements, he's not gonna stop until he gets them.
那又如何  我们就要听之任之吗
Well, so what? We're just supposed to roll over?
菲斯克已经是在案业主了
Fisk is public on this.
如果对他发出禁令
If we tie him up with an injunction,
或许我们可以从证词里挖掘出什么...
maybe we find something in the deposition that we...
得了  福吉  你以为
Oh, come on, Foggy, you think
我们能用取证的办法扳倒此人吗
we're gonna trip this guy up with a deposition?
经历了这么多
After everything that's happened,
你还不明白我们面对的是什么样的人吗
you don't get who we're dealing with?
我们明白
No, we get it!
马特  他是个有钱的混蛋
Matt, he's a rich dickhead
以为他可以买通别人对他听命
who thinks he can pay people off to kiss his ass.
看啊  他跟他的狐朋狗友
Look, he is standing on City Hall
一起站在市政厅前  好像他已经赢了
with his cronies like he's already won.
你知道他看不到
You know he can't see that.
好吧  我们不能允许他们得逞
All right, we can't let him get away with this.
-我知道  -那我们怎么办
- I know. - So, what are we gonna do?
法律和战争的基本原则  知己知彼
Basic tenet of both law and war, know your enemy.
谢谢  孙子  那是什么意思
Thank you, Sun Tzu. What does that actually mean?
就是说  我们接着查
It means we keep digging.
就像凯伦说的  这世界上
Like Karen said, somewhere out there,
肯定有相关文件  有个证人
there's a piece of paper or a witness,
或能指引我们发觉真相的东西
or something that'll lead to the truth.
好  好的
Okay, good.
但是要低调点  别声张
But, do it quietly. Stay under the radar.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
菲斯克向全市发表讲话时  身边有三个人
Three people stood with Fisk when he addressed the city.
联合全球的那人  奥斯利和一个女人
His man from Confed Global, Owlsley and a woman.
媒体称两人关系亲密
One the press said he seemed close with.
对  凡妮莎
Oh, yeah, uh, Vanessa, um...
玛丽安娜  报纸上说她在时尚风景画廊工作
Marianna. It says she works at Scene Contempo Gallery.
或许我该去投资艺术品了
Maybe it's time I invested in some art.
这是我列出的清单
Here's the list that I came up with.
还有别人吗
Anyone else?
一定把里士满列在其中
Make sure Richmond's on the guest list.
他不会来  但不请他会惹他生气
He won't come, but he'll get pissy if he isn't invited.
有访客从西入口进来
You have a visitor coming in through the west entrance.
可以帮你吗
May I help you?
希望可以  我是马修
I hope so. Um, Matthew.
凡妮莎
Vanessa.
凡妮莎  你好
你大概在想
You're probably wondering
看不到的人为什么要来画廊
what a man who can't see is doing in an art gallery.
我不想唐突
I didn't want to be forward.
我的客人告诉我  我的公寓空荡荡的
I'm told by my guests my apartment's a bit stark.
我想或许摆放点画作能增添气氛
I thought maybe some art would warm it up.
我大胆猜测
I'm going to go out on a limb
你的"客人"都是女人吧
and assume these "guests" were women?
反正我不是想哄披萨外卖小哥
Well, I'm not trying to impress the pizza guy.
很好  欣赏艺术不非要有视力
Good. You don't need sight to appreciate art,
但得诚实
but you do need honesty.
-有视力更好  -是啊
- Sight helps. - Sure.
但通过别人的眼睛
But there's something very intimate
感受艺术  是一件很亲密的事
in experiencing art through someone else's eyes.
这句话很煽情  你该拿来用
That's a good line, by the way. You should use it.
我可能会用
I might.
跟我说说你想要什么
So, give me an idea what you're after.
我不确定
I am not sure.
很好  艺术不是家具
Good... art isn't furniture.
如果你完全确定自己想要什么
If you knew exactly what you were looking for,
那就是装修了
you'd be just decorating.
艺术应该让你产生共鸣  对你有触动
Art should speak to you... move you.
比如这个
This one, for example.
是我最喜欢的一件
One of my favorite pieces.
跟我形容一下
Describe it to me.
想象一片各种色调的红色海洋
Imagine a sea of tonal reds.
愤怒的颜色
The color of anger...
狂怒的颜色
of rage...
但也是心的颜色
but also the color of the heart...
还有爱和希望
of love... hope.
这幅画达到了两者间完美的平衡
This strikes the perfect balance between the two.
这听上去有些激进呢
I don't know, it sounds aggressive.
要看你怎么看了
All depends on your point of view.
或许温和一点的吧
Maybe something a little less challenging.
你生活里有男人吗
Tell me, do you have a man in your life?
马修  你在泡我吗
Matthew, are you hitting on me?
不是的  我是问他什么样
No, I just mean, what does he like?
他喜欢什么
What does he respond to?
如果我能了解一个赢得了
If I can get inside the head of the man
你这样有魅力的女人的心的男人
who won the heart of such a charming woman,
那我的决定就有依据了
it would inform my decision.
你可以自己问他啊
Well, you could always ask him yourself.
希望我没有打扰  我就在附近
Hope I'm not interrupting. I was nearby.
没有  我们正说起你呢
Not at all. We were just talking about you.
这样啊
I see.
威尔逊·菲斯克  这是马修
Wilson Fisk, Matthew...
默多克
Murdock.
是啊  那个律师
Oh, yes, the attorney.
我听说了你在地狱厨房的工作
I've heard about all your work in Hell's Kitchen.
我也听说过你的工作
I'm aware of yours as well.
默多克先生想买些画作
Mr. Murdock is thinking of purchasing some art.
他想得到有品位的男人的意见
He was looking for some advice from a man of taste.
很简单  这位女士叫你买什么就买什么
Well, that's simple. Buy whatever the lady tells you.
谢谢
Thank you.
不过我们大概不该说话
Although we probably shouldn't be talking.
我们处于一桩租户案的对立方
I believe we're on opposite sides of a tenancy case.
-是吗  -是的
- Oh, you are? - Yes.
是我最近从徒利先生手中购得的出租楼
The rental properties I recently acquired from Mr. Tully.
但我相信最终的解决方案一定能满足每个人的利益
But I'm sure that will be settled to everyone's benefit.
这个城市因为贫困和衰退
The city has suffered long enough
已经受苦已久
under the burden of poverty and decay.
我们现在有机会...
I believe we have opportunities now with...
威尔逊  默多克先生是顾客  不是捐助人
Wilson, Mr. Murdock is a customer, not a donor.
是啊  抱歉我强行推销了
Yes, I apologize for the hard sell.
这座城市和其未来
This city and its future...
让地狱厨房
Seeing Hell's Kitchen to
发挥全部潜力  对我十分重要
its fullest potential is very important to me.
我也是这么想的
I feel the same way.
凡妮莎  多谢你陪我
Vanessa, thank you so much for your time.
你对你来的目的改主意了吗
Have you changed your mind about what you came for?
不是  我就是得考虑下价钱
No, no, I would just need to consider the cost.
菲斯克先生
Mr. Fisk.
我希望最后的时候  能跟他
I like to have a moment... end of the day...
单独待会儿
just me and him.
或许你可以说句好话
Maybe you could put in a word.
介意我问下  你怎么知道我坐在这里的吗
How did you know I was sitting here, you mind me asking?
你想听简单的答案  还是长的
You want the short answer or the long one?
今早我们聊过之后  我还担心
I was worried you might've gone out and done something foolish,
你去做什么傻事了
after our talk this morning.
我什么都没做呢
I haven't done anything.
暂时还没
Not yet.
听上去很不祥啊
Sounds a bit on the ominous side.
我去见一个跟
I went to visit someone close to the...
魔鬼很亲近的人
close to the Devil.
不是想伤害她  只是想了解他
Not to hurt her, just to get a sense of him.
我想知道他什么样  要怎么样
Of who he is and what it would take to...
才能做到我该做的
do what I have to.
怎么样
And...
你了解到了什么
what did you learn?
他有一个他爱的人
That he has someone he loves...
那人也爱他  会为他的死难过
who loves him, who'd mourn his loss.
没什么事是绝对的  马修
Few things are absolute, Matthew.
就连路西法也曾是天使
Even Lucifer was once an angel.
所以审判和复仇
It's why judgment and vengeance...
最好让上帝去做
are best left to God.
尤其如果你心中并不想杀人
Especially when murder is not in your heart.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
你不是来这儿了吗
You're here, aren't you?
福吉  福吉  福吉
Foggy, Foggy, Foggy...
抱歉
Sorry.
福吉  福吉
Foggy, Foggy...
我知道  如果我杀他  我的灵魂就被诅咒了
I know my soul is damned if I take his life.
但如果我袖手旁观
But if I stand idle, if I...
如果我任他吞噬掉城市
If I let him consume this city,
那些将因此而死  而痛苦的人
all the people that will suffer and die...
不为和杀人之间有一道鸿沟  马修
There is a wide gulf between inaction and murder, Matthew.
他人的恶不是你的善
Another man's evil does not make you good.
历史上  一直有人
Men have used the atrocities
用他人的恶行来辩解
of their enemies to justify their own
他们自己的恶行
throughout history.
你要自问的问题是
So the question you have to ask yourself is...
你纠结的问题
are you struggling with the fact
是你不想杀了这人
that you don't wanna kill this man...
但你别无选择
but have to?
还是你并不是非得杀死他
Or that you don't have to kill him...
但你想杀他
but want to?
"就像泥泞的喷泉  或受了玷污的喷泉
"Like a muddied spring or a polluted fountain
正直之人比邪恶之人更先放弃"
is the righteous man who gives way before the wicked."
箴言篇25章还是什么的  记不住了
Proverbs 25-something, I never can remember.
就是说  正直之人有义务抵抗邪恶
Meaning righteous men have a duty to stand up to evil.
那是一种解释
One interpretation.
另一种解释是  正直之人屈服于罪孽时
Another is that when the righteous succumb to sin,
就像
it is as harmful
公用水井被下了毒一样有害
as if the public well were poisoned.
因为这种行为的黑暗
Because the darkness of such an act...
杀人的黑暗
of taking a life...
会蔓延至朋友  邻里
will spread to friends, neighbors...
至整个社区
the entire community.
如果已经蔓延开了呢
What if it already has?
那我们就不会坐在这里了
Then we wouldn't be sitting here, would we?
我不认为你去见这个女人
I don't believe you went to see this woman
是为了知道该如何杀掉一个人的
for insight into how to kill a man.
我认为
I think...
你或许是去找一个不杀他的理由
maybe you went looking for a reason not to.
福吉  昨晚一直想联系你
Uh, Foggy, um, tried to get a hold of you last night.
嗯  我关了手机
Oh, yeah, turned off my phone.
你没事吧
You okay?
嗯  就是累了
Yeah, just... tired.
跟那个凡妮莎  谈得怎么样
How did it go with that, um... Vanessa woman?
没得到想要的东西
Oh, I didn't get what I needed.
福吉和我查到了些东西
Well, uh, Foggy and I had better luck.
我们查明了在埃琳娜家外面
Um, we identified the assholes that
袭击了我们的混蛋的身份
jumped us outside of Elena's.
是斯图尔特·施密特和约瑟夫·派克
It's a Stewart Schmidt and Joseph Pike.
-你从警方收监照片上找到他们的吗  -不是
- You ID'd them from booking photos? - No, actually...
承包商执照
Contractor's licenses.
你去哪了
And where the hell were you?
散步  清理思绪
Walking, clearing my head.
你不接我电话太闹心了  伙计
Hate when you don't answer my calls, buddy.
我还以为你掉进敞开的井盖里了
I always think you fell down an open manhole or something.
我没事  在案雇主是谁
I'm fine. Who's the employer of record?
维斯莫尔-霍特承包公司
Westmeyer-Holt Contracting,
又是联合全球旗下的一个子公司
another wonderful Global Confed subsidiary.
太好了
Well, that's it. That's great.
我们控告他们人身袭击  让他们供出菲斯克
We press assault charges, get them to flip on Fisk.
不行啊
Yeah, not so much.
我联系了本
I reached out to Ben
他的线人说他们已经不见了
and his sources say that they're off the map.
跟霍夫曼和徒利一样
Just like Hoffman and Tully.
当然了
Of course they are.
太好了  那我们什么都没有
Great, so we have nothing.
也不算没有  看  福吉  给他看
I wouldn't go that far. Here, Foggy, show him the thing.
没错
Right, the thing!
是什么
What thing?
美梦啊
The dream, buddy.
跟我在餐巾上画的那个一样
It's just like the one I drew on the napkin
当时你看不到
that you, uh, couldn't see back when.
尼尔森-默多克律师事务所
有点小啊
It's a little small, isn't it?
大楼规定只能这么大
Building regulations.
而且我们也是  麻雀虽小五脏俱全
Anyway, so are we. We are small but awesome.
我们会有所成就的
And we're gonna make a difference.
我知道有时候感觉不是那样
I know it doesn't feel like it sometimes...
或者说经常  但我们会用法律成就大事
a lot of the time, but we are, with the power of the law.
好
Okay.
你把我拖进了这个小破律所里  默多克
Dragged me into this rinky-dink firm, Murdock...
我永远都谢不够你
and I'll never be able to thank you enough for it.
你不是要亲我吧
You're not gonna kiss me.
-我有点受触动呢  -过来吧
- I'm feeling a little somethin'. - Okay, come here.
尼尔森-默多克  有什么可以帮您的
Nelson and Murdock, how may I help you?
该用上你的杂务工手艺了
Time for those handyman skills.
抱歉  什么
Sorry, what?
什么时候
Uh, when?
是她
It's her.
怎么回事
How did it happen?
邻居看到在楼里出现过的瘾君子
Neighbor saw some junkie they've seen in the building,
拿着她的包逃离了现场
fleeing the scene with her purse.
可能是她找钥匙的时候袭击了她
Probably jumped her while she was fishing for her keys.
凯伦  你还是去外面等着吧
Karen, maybe you should wait outside.
不  不用
No. No, I'm...
她怎么死的
How did she die?
多处刀伤
Multiple stab wounds.
救护车赶到很快  但是...
The ambulance got there quick, but...
我妈说她所指的她的家人都离世了
My mom says all the family she knew about's passed on.
我知道你们在处理她的租约纠纷
I knew you were looking into her tenancy case.
我想着或许你们知道她有什么亲属
I thought you might be able to point us toward the next of kin.
她没有亲人
No, she didn't have anyone.
只有我们
Just us.
我们会做安排的
We'll see to the arrangements.
你们能帮忙真是好心
It's good of you to take that on.
我去告诉法医
I'll let the ME know.
你是个厉害的对手
You are a worthy opponent.
取你性命  是我的荣幸
It is an honor to claim your life.
乔茜酒吧
谢谢
Thanks.
我会继续给你们续杯
I'll keep 'em comin', love.
我们最初接手案子时
When we first took the case,
凯伦和我去了兰德曼-扎克
Karen and I went to Landman and Zack.
玛茜就说埃琳娜楼里有罪犯
Marci talked about a "criminal element" in Elena's building.
租户之死引发民怨  慈善家发表声明
说这就是工人没完成工作就离开的原因
Said that's why the workmen left without finishing the repairs.
因为担心自身安全
"'Cause they feared for their safety."
我以为是瞎扯呢
I thought it was bullshit.
或许就是
Maybe it was.
跟埃琳娜说去啊
Tell that to Elena.
等等  你什么意思
Wait, what are you saying?
我也说不清
Well, I don't know.
就是觉得不对劲
Just doesn't feel right, does it?
这我要喝一杯
I'll drink to that.
你觉得是巧合吗
You think it was a coincidence?
埃琳娜决心留下抗争
Elena decides to stay and fight,
并鼓励她其他的邻居
to rally what's left of her neighbors,
就发生这种事
and this happens.
你觉得菲斯克跟这事有关吗
Do you think Fisk had something to do with this?
说曹操曹操就到
Speak of the devil.
菲斯克又上电视了
Fisk is on the TV again.
乔茜  能把声音打开吗
Hey, Josie, could you turn that up?
不  我并未有幸结识卡德纳斯太太
No, I never had the pleasure of meeting Ms. Cardenas.
我是最近才购下她的大楼
I only recently took possession of her building.
你如何回应
How do you respond to reports
你早知道租户们不安全的报道呢
that you knew the tenement was unsafe?
这没错
That is accurate.
所以我们提供了一份客观的协议金
That's why we offered a substantial sum
以帮助卡德纳斯太太和其邻居
to Ms. Cardenas and her neighbors
另找住处
to help them relocate.
不该让好人被这座城市吞没
We should never let good people get swallowed up by this city.
我为她的死心痛
I mourn this woman's death.
本不该发生的
Didn't have to happen. It should've...
她的去世代表了更严重的问题
Her passing is a symptom of a larger disease...
这问题影响了我们所有人
infecting all of us.
那就是恐惧
Disease of fear...
殡仪馆
Funeral home.
害怕爆炸  害怕警察被杀
...fear of bombings, fear of cop killings.
喂
Hello?
-害怕一个戴面具的疯子  -是我
- Fear of a masked psychopath. - Yeah, that's me.
嗯  我要做些安排
Yeah, I need to make arrangements.
不该让那样的人劫持我们的城市
We shouldn't let people like that take our city from us.
我们得团结一致
We need to stand together.
让那种人知道他们不会得逞
Let them know that they will fail...
因为我们相信我们能有所作为
because we believe we can make a difference.
因为他们只是懦夫
'Cause they are cowards!
不敢走出阴影
Afraid of stepping out of the shadows.
不敢支持卡德纳斯太太这样的人
Afraid of standing up for people like Mrs. Cardenas.
对不起  对不起
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
菲斯克先生  这对即将到来的慈善晚会有何影响
Mr. Fisk, how does this affect the upcoming benefit?
到此为止  谢谢各位
That will be all. Thank you.
-菲斯克先生  -到此为止了
- Mr. Fisk... - No more questions.
-谢谢各位  -我们要如何解决这个疯子
- Thank you very much. - What can we do about this psycho...
天呐  他听上去几乎是真心的
Jesus, he almost sounds like he means it.
我觉得他是
I think he does.
他还说面具男是疯子
And he's calling the man in the mask a psycho?
希望埃琳娜的事能查到他门口
I hope they trace what happened to Elena right to his doorstep.
他绝不会那样暴露自己的
He'd never expose himself like that.
而且  半数警察大概都被他攥在手中
Plus, half the force is probably in his pocket.
那就祈祷面具男找到他吧
Well, then, let's pray the Mask gets his hands on him.
把他的头敲下来
Knocks his goddamn head off.
你信教吗  凯伦
You religious, Karen?
我父母信
My parents were.
或许就因此我不信
That's probably why I'm not.
你呢
You?
天主教
Catholic.
有用吗
Does it help?
在这样的事上
With things like this?
今天没有
Not today.
我喝得差不多了
I think I've had enough.
-替我跟福吉道别  -嗯
- Tell Foggy I'll see him in the morning. - Yeah.
马特
Hey, Matt.
如果有上帝
If there is a God...
如果他在乎
and if he cares at all about...
我们任何人
about any of us...
菲斯克会得到应有的惩罚
Fisk will get what he deserves.
你一定得相信
You have to believe that.
我相信
I do.
看着
Look at it.
-他在哪  -我不知道
- Where is he? - I don't know.
告诉我你知道些什么
Tell me what you do know.
好吧  你要知道什么我都告诉你
All right, all right, I'll tell you anything you want.
求你  别再伤害我了
Just, please, stop hurting me!
你是真的  你是真的
Hey, you're real, you're... You're real...
-包是哪来的  -什么包
- Where'd you get the purse? - What purse?
撒谎  可不明智
Lying? Bad idea.
求你  住手  我病了
Please, stop! I'm... I'm sick.
好吧  好吧  那个包
Okay! Okay, the purse!
我告诉你是谁抢来的
I'll tell you who snatched it...
听着  我今晚已经伤了不少人了
Listen, I've hurt a lot of people tonight
就为了得到我需要的信息
to get what I need to know.
杀了卡德纳斯太太的混蛋
The asshole that killed Mrs. Cardenas
就在这里吸毒
shoots up at this address,
喜欢廉价薄荷糖
likes cheap menthols.
觉得能掩盖他那口烂牙的臭味
Thinks it covers the stench of his rotting teeth.
但没用的
It doesn't.
谁付钱让你去的
Who paid you?
-不  我没有  -是菲斯克吗
- No, I don't, I don't... - Was it Fisk?
是菲斯克吗
Was it Fisk?
是不是威尔逊·菲斯克
Was it Wilson Fisk?
不  我不知道  求你  住手
No, I don't know! Please, stop! Please!
给我个停手的理由
Give me a reason to!
我不知道他们叫什么
I don't know their names.
我不知道  是他们找到了我
I don't! They found me.
他们带我去了水上的一间仓库
They took me to a warehouse on the water...
81号码头
Pier 81.
我并不想做的
I didn't wanna do it, man.
我发誓  我不想的
I swear. I didn't wanna do it!
但我好难受  我好难受啊
But I was hurting. I was hurting, man.
闭嘴
Shut up!
你要去自首
You're gonna turn yourself in...
向15分局的布莱特·马霍尼警员自首
to Sergeant Brett Mahoney at the 15th Precinct.
否则  我就会找到你
If you don't, I'll find you.
下次  我不会停手了
And next time, I'm not gonna stop.
我不是为你而来
I didn't come here for you.
但你找到了我
But I am the one you have found.
之前在码头  你跟那男孩在一起
You were at the docks with the boy.
你也在
As were you...
跟那老蠢货在一起
with the old fool.
我们倒是没预料到
That was unexpected.
我跟他的战争无关
I'm not part of his war.
但你却帮了他
Yet you aided him.
并因此给我招致麻烦
And in the act, caused me displeasure.
是菲斯克派你来的吗
Did Fisk send you?
他是为这个付钱让那个瘾君子
Is that why he paid that junkie to...
一个女人死了  为了什么呢
A woman is dead, and for what?
就为把我引入陷阱吗
Just to lure me into some kind of a trap?
你不是来了吗
You are here, are you not?
我知道楼里没人
I knew no one was in the building.
之前在俄国人那里犯过这个错误
Made that mistake with the Russians once.
吸取了教训
Learned from it.
但你却不知道我在
But you did not know I was here.
是啊
No...
你放慢了心跳
you slowed your heart...
降低了体温
lowered your body temperature.
那老蠢货教了你一些我们的本事
The old fool has taught you in our ways.
我说了我跟他不是一伙儿的
I told you I'm not with him.
但你仍是名勇士
Yet you're still a warrior...
应该像勇士一样死去
deserving of a warrior's death.
我是为菲斯克而来
I came here for Fisk.
看来只能拿你将就了
Guess I'll have to settle for you.
我给了你尊重
I show you respect.
你要是聪明  就该以礼相还
You would be wise to return the courtesy.
尊重是要自己赢得的
You'll have to earn it.
该死  抱歉
Shit, sorry.
再来一瓶好吗
Hey, can I get another bottle over here?
不用  乔茜  福吉
No, no, never mind, Josie. Hey, hey, Foggy.
福吉  我喝够了  你已经
Foggy, I've had enough, and you have had...
喝多了
way, way past that.
这是守灵  凯伦
It's a wake, Karen.
守灵就该喝酒的
People drink at wakes.
你不用喝了
You don't need it.
知道为什么
You know why?
因为感觉很糟
'Cause it sucks.
我知道
I know.
你会说西班牙语
You speak Spanish.
该怎么为不该死的人
What's a good toast for the people that should...
祝酒
That should still...
我就该像马特说的那样  叫她拿钱
I should have told her to take the money like Matt said.
不不不  福吉
No, no, no, no, Foggy...
那不怪你  好吗
it's not your fault, okay?
我小时候的地狱厨房  是个烂地方
The Hell's Kitchen I grew up in was a real shithole.
但那时它还有灵魂
But it had a heart, you know?
我和马特  我们学会了规矩
Me and Matt... we learned the law...
任何遵守规矩
how to play by the rules.
我们本想帮助我们小时候的那些邻居
We were gonna help the people that we grew up with.
让他们像菲斯克那样的大人物一样有个机会
Give 'em the same shot as the big boys like Fisk.
都是白扯
It's all bullshit.
这都是
It's all just...
我们为了撑过每一天自欺欺人的谎言
lies that we tell ourselves to make it through one more day.
不  我不信
No, I don't... I don't believe that.
我不能相信
I can't.
我们要怎么做
What are we supposed to do...
怎么对付一个拥有一切的人
against somebody that owns everything?
一个控制每个人的人
Everyone?
我们怎么对付那样的人啊
What can we do to somebody like that?
你唯一能做的
The only thing you can...
就是让他们付出代价
you make them pay.
你打得很英勇
You have fought well.
这还不够
It is... not enough.
谢谢
Thank you.
信越来越成问题了
Nobu was becoming an issue.
多谢你
I appreciate you...
替我除掉他
removing him from concern.
你就希望我这么做
You... wanted me to do this.
如果情况理想
In a perfect world,
你们会自相残杀至死
you would have taken each other out, but...
但人生并不理想  不是吗
it isn't a perfect world, is it?
暂时还不
Not yet.
老实说
To be honest...
用的时间比我想的要久
it took longer than I expected.
信并不介意  他能冥想好几个小时
Nobu didn't mind. He meditated for hours.
但我做不太好
I find it difficult to meditate.
我的大脑不肯安静下来
My mind, it won't quiet.
算是个性格缺陷吧
It's a character flaw, I suppose.
我们都有缺点
We all have them.
比如你
You, for instance.
你表现出了对女人和孩子的
You've demonstrated an emotional weakness
情绪弱点
for children and women.
我想对老人应该也是如此
I assumed that would extend to the elderly.
所以我就放了饵
So I baited the hook.
你就上钩了
Here you are.
你杀了她
You took her life...
就为了吸引我的注意
just to get my attention?
信让我别无选择
Nobu forced my hand in the matter.
我的选择因为现实而有限
My options, they were limited by necessity.
她的离世并不让我快乐
I took no pleasure in her passing.
我要杀了你
I'm... gonna kill you.
来吧
Take your shot.
真令人失望
It's disappointing.
韦斯利
Wesley.
在码头上安排人
Put men on the dock.
如果见到面具男  就打死他
If they see the Mask, put a bullet in him.
信呢
What about Nobu?
让他烧吧
Let him burn.
马特
Matt!
开门啊  马特
Come on, Matt.
我得跟你谈谈  马特
I need to talk to you, Matt.
我们得坚持下去  马特
We need to keep going, Matt.
我们得给那混蛋定罪
We gotta nail that bastard to the wall.
我们要让他付出代价  为埃琳娜
We gotta make him pay... for Elena...
为一切一切
for everything.
马特
Matt?
你没事吧  马特
Are you okay in there? Matt?
马特
Matt!
Matt?
是我
It's me.
我听到撞击声
I heard a crash.
不是那种好玩的做爱声
Not the fun, sexy-time kind, but...
更像是
more of the...
我摔倒了  爬不起来那种
I've-fallen-and-I-can't-get-up variety.
马特
Matt?
如果这屋里有不该出现在这里的人
If anyone who's in here is not supposed to be,
我会狠狠收拾你的  我没开玩笑
I will mess you up. I'm not kidding.
马特呢  你把他怎么了
Where's Matt? What'd you do to him?
该死
Shit.
马特
Matt?